[Music]
hey hey welcome to the week to camp with
Tinkercad ice what we're going to be
doing this week is we're going to be
learning about a software tool that's
called tinker camp
available at Tinkercad calm and
Tinkercad is the focus of the camp for
this week if you do want some more stuff
with tinker you can go look at the the
camp page for for last week's camp
there's all kinds of stuff with with
tinker's botha why but you're hopefully
here particular tad and what we're going
to be doing is we're going to be
learning about the software tools that
are available here this camp is kind of
appropriate for fourth graders up
through eighth graders I've got one in
my family that fits that description
how would you like to introduce yourself
and she is in fourth grade and she's
going to be following along with
Tinkercad with us if you were watching
last week we had the whole family here
but this time it's just me and McKinley
and so what we're going to be doing is
we're going to be learning about three
different tools that Tinkercad offers
first off what is taken cad Tinkercad is
a website that's completely free it's
meant to encourage young people to
become makers maybe you've heard the
term like makerspace or 3d printing or
things like that but Tinkercad is all
about helping kids become makers and
their tools are actually really really
good I to the point that we use them in
college classes sometimes right there's
three different tools there's 3d
designer which is what we're learning
about today
there's circuits which we're going to
learn about for three days so circuits
is Tuesday Wednesday Thursday so the
heart of this camp is circuits and that
on Friday the very last day is going to
be about codeblocks and so hopefully
you're able to sign in on Tinkercad
using the the credentials that I sent
you and it's fine that we started
learning so we're going to learn a new
3d software tool we're going to build a
couple of projects today I'm just going
to show you kind of like my solutions
one of our solutions is going to be a
rocket ship so here is the rocket ship
and so we're just going to kind of be
learning about different techniques to
do 3d modeling
and then we're also going to build
another one called a house and this
house is actually following along with
the tutorial that someone at Tinkercad
made he made a blog post about building
a Tinkercad house and so those are our
two projects today so let's go ahead and
get started so to get started what I
want to do first is I want to actually
work the tutorials with you we're going
to kind of work I'm going to accelerate
the pace but feel free to always pause
the video whenever you like so we want
to work the tutorials through tutorials
are called like place it and move it and
things like that so where do you find
their tutorials well there's a bunch of
ways to get there I kind of like to
click on the link at the top right that
says learn so go ahead and click on this
link that says learn and what you can do
we're going to make you screen for here
is you can learn about 3d modeling or
you can learn about circuits or you
could learn about code blocks and today
of course is 3d modeling so 3d modeling
is very important because I let you
build things that you design for the
physical world it's also really big in
Tinkercad to make things in 3d print
them and if you happen to have access to
a 3d printer then you can actually just
print the things you make which is
amazing you can also order 3d prints
with that cost money right so let's go
ahead and start learning about their
lessons and starters so I think that
they're called starters so I'm gonna
click on see all starters so when I
click on see all starters it takes me to
a page like this and this is what I was
looking for I place it view it move it
rotate it size it and grow it and align
it so there's 7 tutorials I don't know
you're like 7 tutorials so it's gonna
take like an hour I they're all short
right so go ahead and click on the
starter 4 places and the nice thing is
is that once you finish place it
there'll be a link to where you can just
go on to the next one so this is the
Tinkercad 3d modeling environment so you
can see that the main thing here is the
the workplane where you work you've also
got like shapes that you can drag on
here and then this box over on the left
this is the two
- all right so those are the different
things to work today one thing that I do
recommend you use is a mouse
so you'll see why as we get into it but
if you're a 3d modeler you use the right
mouse button the left mouse button
scroll wheel you'll use it also like
it's way better than a trackpad so I do
recommend that you get a mouse can you
do it without a mouse sure you got is it
better with the mouse alright so here's
the placeit tutorial so this shows you
how to actually like add things to your
model and so the goal is we're going to
add one of these orange sorry red cubes
this block and the goal of this tutorial
is to try to get a position right there
right so what you need to do is you need
to grab it from the side and try your
best just to put it right on the orange
on line I know I think I can pretty well
hit mine but even if I miss it's okay
but my goal is to try to like drop it
right on there if you miss by a little
bit that's alright you could always try
to fix it
one way you can fix it is you can zoom
in here's a plus button that will kind
of help you zoom in and then you can
click it and you can just try to try to
drag it around but I'm trying to get it
like right on there little preview
window and as soon as I think I've got
it there that I'm ready for the next
step so pretty easy first step and it
actually turns out that that's the whole
tutorial right well that's one of the
seven tutorials if you succeed in
getting it to the perfect spot they
reward you with stars so there are
lessons are very short and directed this
one was showing you the main thing you
do and that's grabbing things and
dropping them into the workplane you
don't need to grab other things I'm just
kind of showing you that that's that's
kind of how Tinkercad works is you grab
things from over there and you drop them
once you're done with this you can click
on done and then it says hey you've made
it time for the next lesson for view it
so you click on continue so one lesson
down six more to go and we're gonna
start learning about take your pad so
this lesson again you can pause it if
you prefer to just read the instructions
but I'm gonna kind of walk you through
it together the first thing it's telling
you
do is this this is all about view it so
it's all about viewing it from different
directions you can see that the block
that we're viewing is an awesome like
part because it just says the word front
right on the front
I says the word top are on the top so
the first thing that's telling you do
you to do is to grab this little they
call it the view tube so if you grab it
you can kind of move it around
that's kind of cool so you can kind of
see it from the top from the front from
the right from the left you just kind of
move it around wherever you can even see
the bottom on this thing so the view
cube is one important way to try to like
navigate and see what's what I'm gonna
click on next year the next thing that's
important is the zoom tool you can zoom
by clicking on this plus that's one way
to zoom in and so that's a good way to
zoom in now to be honest you can also
click on the minus here to zoom out I
rarely ever use these plus and minus
buttons personally I use sometimes I use
this fit button it's nice it just kind
of makes it fit but other than that I
use my scroll wheel on my mouse so if I
scroll out I kind of zoom way out and if
I scroll in then i zoom way in right so
if you have a mouse with a scroll wheel
you'll never need those two buttons ever
again because you just use your scroll
wheel and then find that being good at
CAD is actually kind of like like being
able to type right like when you want
something to happen you you can just do
it without even thinking about it also
say that the viewcube here you can use
it to rotate around but there's actually
a better way to rotate around McKinley
do you know what the better way to
rotate around this so this is actually
way easier than the cube so I never
actually used the cube anymore once I
learned this trick if I have a mouse and
I have a right mouse button I can click
and hold the right mouse button and I
can kind of use that to rotate it around
which is kind of cool I said thanks the
question of what happens if you like
don't want to just rotate if you want to
this if you happen to have a mouse with
a center wheel you can push on it and
you can drag around and it'll let you
pay in side-to-side so some people call
right mouse click orbit so you can orbit
around your part and then the mouse
wheel would beep and so those are some
some useful things I think it's going to
tell us some more tips here so oh here's
the right mouse button tricks oh yeah
that one's definitely a big one other
tricks are that if you want to view
something straight from the front you
can click on the cube here and it'll
zoom you to the front also if you look
at there's an arrow above the cube you
can flip it to view it straight from the
top another thing that I don't think
they tell you about in the tutorial but
I kind of like to do I get your view
towards from the top I like to switch
the view between what's called
orthographic and projection view this
sounds awfully advanced right um but
let's click on this bottom button and
maybe to see the difference a
orthographic view is not something
that's like possible with your eye and a
real object because obviously there's no
way to see this side and the side and
the side and the side in a real world
that's really what you would do if you
were standing here you'd see a
perspective and then would be hidden
right it's like the size of it hidden
but an orthographic view lets you see
things as if it's like perfectly
straight down from the top so if you're
if your vantage point was infinitely far
away with the telescope right um so I
find the perspective and orthographic
view very useful as I'm building models
and we'll just see how it comes up when
we start doing things but I think I'm
starting to get the hang of rotating
around using my right mouse button
zooming using the mouse wheel if I want
to I can use the hold down the mouse
wheel to pan and then whenever you want
to you can just click on view all and
it'll kinda fix it up for you so there's
nothing tried to do in this tutorial so
I get my stars I just first successfully
clicking the next button 3 times did you
get fancy stars McKinley all right so
we're doing good so we're done with view
it as I mentioned there were 7
so there's two of them that are done and
we've got five to go so we're chugging
away through these things
this one is move it so I'm going to
click on next here and it says what it
wants you to do is I want you to move
these blocks tour they're perfectly
aligned in these areas now one way to do
this tutorial is just to use the view
that they've got and you single click on
one and then you drag and move it now
whenever you're doing these tutorials
sometimes things go great and you just
put it right in the spot sometimes they
go lousy let's say I clicked on one of
these blocks and I'm gonna do something
wrong instead of grabbing like where
there's no handles and moving it that's
what you're supposed to do let's say I
accidentally grabbed like this white
square and then I started dragging it
and then started getting taller my big
oh no I didn't mean to make it taller I
just made a huge undo is your friends so
you click on undo so as I mentioned one
way to do this is to just kind of get it
into the position other things you can
do is you can practice some of those
other skills you've been working on so
for example this puzzle might be easiest
to solve if I viewed it from the top and
it might be easiest if I switched it to
an orthographic projection and it might
be easiest if I kind of use my zoom
skills that I learned to kind of like
move to where I could see this thing
better right and then there I know I
just crushed that alright so I put it
right right into that and so I really
like getting good at at using my legs
oome tools so here I'm just using my
scroll wheel to check that one that one
looks good and I like to use the pan
sometimes the pan is pushed down on the
scroll wheel and I can just kind of see
that all these things look right and so
now I've just kind of got one left to go
and I want to move this guy right here
to be right into this water and I can
zoom in on it or I can hit this fit
button and I can just kind of see yep it
fits everything that I want now to zoom
out
I can click off of that object I can
click on the fit again and so it'll kind
of fit everything and then before I
leave something what I like to do is I
like to put it back into
it's called an isometric view kind of a
side view and I like for it to be viewed
as the perspective so there I have
successfully moved my four blocks
perfectly in the little orange things
and hopefully I'll get stars when I
click on the the next button I must have
done it perfect
I get stars they're kind of mean to you
if you don't get stars one or two things
happen either you didn't have perfect or
they're a little program glitched and
then you miss the stars right but you
should get stars I quote McKinley did
you get stars on that one well so if
you're having problems what I want you
to do is I want you to pause the video
and play with it until you get there
practice makes perfect don't feel bad if
it takes you a while right like I click
and and it's like everything goes
perfect and then when you do it it's
like everything goes wrong I assure you
that whenever I started everything went
wrong for me too it's just that I've
been doing this stuff for a long time I
next tutorial what are we up to here I
think this is for is rotated so we're
learning about how to manipulate our
objects they're easy to drag and bring
on to the screen but then how you
manipulate on my is what's important so
you can see that this one there's going
to be three different challenges we've
got to rotate these cubes in different
ways so what I'm gonna do is I'm going
to kind of zoom in on one at a time I
could click on it here and say fit and
that would kind of get me zoomed in on
it better but you can also use your pan
tools and so you kind of get get where
you look at this one
so this one I need to rotate you know in
this direction to make it match up with
the little ghost image so I'm gonna
click on my block here that I'm wanting
to rotate and I've got to find the right
handle let's pause for a minute and look
at these handles so the one that I want
is this one back here this is a rotate
side to side but let's look at some of
the other handles you notice that each
corner has a little white handle so if I
wanted to resize the box I could grab
one of these handles so I could affect
like the the size of the bottom here
each edge on the bottom has a little
black handle black handles if you want
to pull it in just one direction those
black handles are nice there's also this
little
like cone thing here the cone will let
me move the block up whereas the white
handle would let me make the block
taller so I make sense so the one that I
want right now is this guy back here so
what I'm gonna do is I'm going to click
and drag on it so when you click on it
and drag nips old one will have in
trouble
definitely takes six times so I'll click
on this again so they're popped up right
so I'm gonna click and drag on it now
I'm holding down the left mouse button
and I'm moving it around you'll notice
that line right now is moving in kind of
big steps right that's because I'm
currently inside that circle so you kind
of imagine that there's a circle there
if I was outside the circle so farther
away I can move it a very exact amount
it's like if I wanted to move it exactly
like 41 degrees I could do that outside
the circle but if you bring your mouse
inside the circle then that'll let you
move it a big step amount right so I
want exactly 45 degrees so I want to
kind of be inside the circle so there
I've got that one moved to the right
spot one down two more to go
so the next one and again pause it for
you if you need more time the next one
the first thing I've got to do is I
gotta find the right handle so you know
which handle do I want well there's this
handle there's that handle those would
rotate me insert directions aha the one
that I want is actually this bottom
handle because what needs to happen is
it needs to rotate using this bottom
direction towards the 45 degrees again
as I click on it so it's kind of like a
you click and then I'm just I'm holding
down that left mouse button and drag I
can move inside that circle to do like
exact big movements or I can be outside
that circle to to like really fine grain
control and as long as we hit 45 it
doesn't matter what you use so if I do
45 exactly using the outside then that
I'm all set there but it's sometimes
easier to use the inside to solve
something like this I also mentioned
that you can type so let's say I put it
down I put it at 32 on accident oh I
just let go of it at 32 and then I just
click on
45 and I type four or five hit enter and
that also gets me right great so I'm
doing good
I've got one more to go you can see
we're being able to get around your
drawing is a very useful skill so I kind
of come over to the next one here with a
combination of right-mouse orbits and I
use that Center scroll we'll hold down
pain so this one I think you kind of get
the idea I want to figure out which axes
to rotate it about and I want to use
this axes that is on the back so I'm
going to click and drag and I'm old I
will hide what's going on here I'm going
to use the inside the circle option so
that I get a nice perfect 45 and it's
easy to do and I like I know it should
happen is I should have them all three
rotated to be honest I didn't read the
instructions at all because it was
obvious what I needed to do based on the
illustrations I hit next and I get my
stars going good for you alright so
let's move on to the next one I've
honestly lost track of how many we're in
this is what this this is five well
pretend like it's five five out of seven
McKinley just asked how many more we got
and I said well there's like three more
but this is how you learn a tool right
so before you can do amazing things you
got to learn at first rate this one
we're resizing things so we're going to
use those other handles to do different
sizing things so this one this first
challenge is to make it wider and really
the the best way to do it is to grab
this black handle on this side and then
the black hand on the other side and
move it to where it matches the block
now there are other ways you can do it
you can grab white handles as well but I
think those black handles are going to
do it again here those black handles are
really what's best because they'll move
it in just that direction if you wanted
to move it with a white handle you
totally could it would it would work
just the same but a white handle you got
to be careful that you don't
accidentally move it in a different
direction
what you reading right so I do recommend
those black handles and then they kind
of had me do it three times I like
Tinkercad that you can click on a block
and then once you click on it like
they'll let you grab the handles even if
it's like not physically possible right
it's like this back one here I wanted to
kind of like move it to the right spot
if you think you can hit it from this
view feel free to go ahead and try to
match it up perfect but if you don't
think that you can hit it get good at
orbiting around and get to where you can
see it like really well and zoom in as
you as you need and getting good at zoom
and orbit is just as important as
actually succeeding with the tutorial
the last one needs to go in multiple
directions multiple directions I'm fine
with whatever you want to do to solve it
you could grab on each black handle one
by one or just to kind of because it's
different I will choose to use the white
format handle this time so I'm going to
put this corner right into that edge I'm
gonna jump around to the back of my
drawing using using my right mouse orbit
I'm gonna get myself to the right
position here and then I'm gonna grab
this handle and bring it this way and
you can see how if you do a great job of
getting Tori you can see things then
these these assignments become very
reason and so now I'm finished with this
one so if it all works I'm gonna hit
next these are the instructions which I
didn't really need and so I'm gonna hit
next again and I should get stars if
it's alright yes my stars they added the
star animation it does actually like
helps this it doesn't make you happy
when you see stars alright so that was
size it up I think that there's two more
so I think there's fruit bit and
Alliance is what I think is coming
alright grouping so grouping is an
important concept in Tinkercad so in
Tinkercad you can only make like you can
only add cylinders and
locks and things like this but I said
that hey we're gonna make like a rocket
ship or we're gonna make like a house
and sometimes you need things like group
together and also sometimes you need to
make holes and things and the way you do
that in Tinkercad is you take these two
parts like a cylinder and a square and
this cube in this case and you make them
into like one part right that's that's
what this tutorial is going to show us
and the way you do it is you click on
the objects you want to group so these
two things on the left are going to be
grouped together and so what you need to
do is you need to click on the cylinder
and then you need to hold down the shift
key so it says like there's a hint in
here about like how to hold the shift
key hold down the shift key and then
click on the other one right now when
you've selected them both it should say
like shapes 2 in here and it'll it'll
have like handles that are big enough to
good goal thing and what you want to do
is you want to group it together so I
click on this button up here which is
group now what it does when you make a
group is it takes those two parts and it
makes them the same color it also makes
it to where they're essentially just
like a single solid mass now mine turned
orange wait why did it turn orange I'm
if I do it differently like if I select
the cube and then I hold down shift I
select the cylinder and then I say group
it turns red right but it makes them the
same color by default by the way if the
same color thing bothers you you can
always change it after you make it click
on the color and then say multicolor and
then it'll go back to the multiple
colors that you originally but it is
still one piece right now grouping
solids is useful you'll use that
sometime but actually what's even more
useful is grouping things where one of
them is a hole and the other is a solid
that's how you drill holes and take your
pen I'm a neat system so you'll notice
that over here maybe you saw this
already
you can add solid pieces these are all
these or you can also add holes of
things also for any solid you add you
can make it into a hole so here they've
added two parts there is a cube and then
this cube has another part in it which
is a hole but they're two separate parts
but now watch what happens if I click on
this one hold down shift click on this
one and then I click on this group
button which by the way is also
controlled G if you like short fakies
now once I do that I groups them and if
I rotate it I can see that I've just
drilled a hole straight through my block
right so that is how you do cutouts and
take a pad and it's actually a pretty
cool system by the way if you ever want
to ungroup something you can click on it
and you can click on ungroup I know have
your two two pieces back but that is a
group cool very useful take the guide
skill let's click on next and there's
more instructions here which we didn't
really need and then we get our stars
alright last one I think if it's not the
last one then you know we'll do more but
I'm pretty sure this last one this last
one is called alignment now aligning
things in Tinkercad I can be done a
couple of ways when we do our follow-ups
we'll do it like some manual ways but in
this tutorial we're going to learn about
like magically aligning things quickly
let's go ahead and learn more so here's
what we're gonna do the instructions say
to select all three boxes so click on
this box hold down shift click on this
box hold down shift and click on this
box and now what we want to do is we
want to pretend like we want these like
all be aligned like maybe vertically or
maybe I'll flap together no matter what
you want to do to align and you click on
this button right here this is a line
which is just L now with a line they
don't know how you want to align it so
maybe you want to align it until you
just use I'm just hovering I'm not
pressing any buttons maybe you want to
align it tour they're all like in the
same line this direction right so if I
click this thing here and you can see
what it would do is it would bring them
toward they're all in that plane right
if I clicked on this one here it would
bring them all over to this side if I
clicked on this one here and bring them
all to that side and you can see that
these little
black circles are hints for where you
could take things right and so it just
depends on what you're trying to do
which one you want in this tutorial what
they ask you to do is they ask you to
bring them all to the front so the first
black circle they want you to actually
click on is this one right here
I'm gonna click on this little black
circle and it brings them all to the
front by the way if you if you didn't
want to do something like you made a
goof undo always your best friend right
but I did want to do that and then after
I've aligned them this way the tutorial
says to bring them all down to the floor
together well if I wanted to bring them
all down to the floor together that's
going to be this handle over here
because it's gonna align them select you
can see this axes this will bring them
to the top bring them through the middle
and then that would bring them all to
the bottom one right so there's always
with a line there's like top middle and
so a line is something that we're going
to use at our tutorials together so I'm
going to go ahead and click on next to
see what instructions they've got and
sure enough I get my get my stars
so I'm gonna click on done now normally
here's where the next tutorial would pop
up but we have now finished all of the
tutorials I probably Kinley so that's
gonna be really loud so now we're ready
to like go back and make a new project
well whenever I click that button it
took me back to here and I didn't ruin I
don't really know where I'm at whenever
you're completely Rost click on the
Tinkercad logo and it'll kind of take
you back to your dashboard right so what
we want to do is we want to build a
rocket ship so here's a finished model
what we're going to build but of course
I don't want this I want a new design so
go ahead and click on create new design
now when you click on create new design
what it does is it picks a name for your
project and it saves it with that silly
name it's kind of fun to see what what's
the silly name is well I got a crazy one
there bodacious I don't even know how to
say it so I'm gonna call this rocket
it's not a rocket yet but it will be so
what I want to do is I want to draw my
rocket on this works
now my work plane right now is in
millimeters so you've got to get good at
different units so we work sometimes
millimeters sometimes here in the u.s.
we work in inches and there's lots of
different things and this platform right
now is 200 millimeters wide by 200
millimeters long that's actually a
little bit big for my rocket so if you
wanted to use a smaller grid click here
where it says edit grid and you can see
that right now it's using millimeters
but if you wanted to switch to like
inches or bricks you could do that and
the width is 200 by 200 what I'm going
to do is I'm going to change it to be
100 by 100 and you can have these point
0 0 or not they don't matter just so
long as it's 100 by 100 and when I click
on update grid it gets smaller and this
is a more appropriate size for the
rocket that we're going to build
together so the rocket then we're going
to build it's going to have a cylinder
as the like main fuselage and so you're
just going to go and drop a cylinder
onto your work plane I sometimes suffer
from OCD things I like for things to be
centered it doesn't actually matter in
fact I'm gonna be like re-centering and
all the time today
I just because it bugs me but really it
doesn't matter if it's centered so you
can see that when I brought dropped my
cylinder on here these blocks are each
10 millimeters like these major dividers
so this cylinder must be 20 millimeters
around it's radius is technically 10
millimeters and then it's also got some
height to it as well the height on it
right now is 20 millimeters let's go
ahead and change that let's make it a
little taller so to make it taller grab
this white handle and just grow it until
it's at 40 now I like to just grow it
until he hits 40 exactly but remember
that if you do gouf by one you say or no
hoops I like to know what 41 you can
always once you let go just click on the
number and then change it to what you
wanted
sometimes typing is actually easier than
getting at this perfect so here's the
fuselage of my rocket my rocket is
currently orange I personally I never
see rockets that are orange so I'm going
to change the color so click here where
it says solid and it's got the orange
color and pick a good rocket right
maybe this gray or maybe one of these
other degrees whatever you consider a
good rocket color if you like orange
rocket into a pink Rockets feel free to
make an orange repeat rocket but I'm
gonna make it so next thing I want to do
is I want a cone on the tip of my rocket
so I'm gonna drag a cone over now
whenever you first drag something into
your model you can try to put it into
the right spot but sometimes it's hard
right it's like I want to put it right
here on top well don't do that because
I'm what's gonna really happen is it's
gonna put it somewhere on your work
plane if I try to put it on top here
it's actually gonna put it way back in
the distance low cone so I'm just gonna
set it right up here right next to my
silver
now what I want to do here is I want to
somehow get it from here up to there
right so what I'm gonna do first is I'm
gonna move it up
it's kind of funny that it is a cone and
you have to grab the code but go ahead
and grab this cone and move it up 40
right so you can see that I'm moving it
up now I went off the screen here right
so I wasn't able to get to 40 but I can
always just click on the number it got
up to 37 and then I moved it up 40 so I
didn't change the height of the cone and
I just moved moved it up so you can see
that now it is been moved up it's the
same height as the cylinder which is
good now what I want to do is I want
them to be like on top of each other ah
that's where a line can be useful so I'm
going to click on my cylinder and then
I'm going to hold down shift and I'm
going to click on my code now what I
want to do is I want to align them a
line is a shortcut key that's up here
again if I work in a different pace than
you don't worry about it just go at the
pace that works for you but I'm going to
line them and I want them to be aligned
in two different directions I want them
to be aligned in this direction and in
this direction
and by doing that I put one perfectly on
top of the other now where it put it
perfectly on top of one another is not
the middle of the word plain that's fine
there's no reason to be in the middle or
plain except Frank can handle it so I
want to put it back to the middle now
for me to put it back to the middle I
think it's the easiest to do if I if I
view from the top so I'm going to choose
to click on the top on the view cube
here and it zooms me to the top I find
it's easier to do things from a top view
whenever I'm in the perspective mode so
I'm going to switch out of orthographic
and so projection mode just kind of like
makes it look flat which is nice and now
I'm going to choose to move my rocket
back to the middle to choose it I drag a
window around it and that'll select all
the pieces and then I'm gonna grab where
there's no handle so somewhere where
there's no handle and then that'll just
let me I drag it around I've got it
perfectly in the center again isn't that
better alright so now it's perfectly
centered and I'm gonna rotate it back to
where I can see it I'm gonna switch it
back into perspective mode cool
so our lock rocket is looking more and
more like a rocket it kind of looks like
a grain silo right now if you'd like to
change the tip of your rocket you can
mine is currently purple I've got no
problems with purple but I'll switch my
into a red you can make your rocket be
any color you'd like
so our rocket currently looks like a
grain silo the only thing we're missing
is we're missing fins right so we need
to thin this thing so it's kind of nice
to look around and see if there's any
tools that can kind of like help you
make fins so it looks like there's two
types of stars now you could use either
type of stars but I happen to know that
this blue one has more like features
that you can do the yellow one is a
five-pointed star
but this one has more features so I drug
the blue star and drop it over here
ah cool so
neat already all right so the first
thing I want to do with my star is I
want to change how many points it's got
right so this is kind of fun but you can
add as many additional points as you'd
like so it's kind of neat that you can
do that you can take it down as low as 3
I choose to have four fins on my rock
so I'm going to change mine to 4 if you
want a different number of fins on your
rocket that's just fine other things
that I can change is I can change the
radius I wanted my rocket down wider
fins or smaller fins to be honest I
didn't really want to change that so
here's what I do this is silly whenever
I change something on my go I didn't
want to change that I set it to
something outrageous and then I hit undo
and I set it to something outrageous so
that I can see when I hit on new that
it's actually back to what it was
supposed to be now what I do want to do
is I do want to kind of like thin up the
fins because like they could be like
super fat fins it's like they actually
look really pretty thin right the next
thing I want to do is I want to change
the color of my fins you could use
whatever color you wanted maybe you've
got black fins on your rocket I think in
one of my examples I used like an orange
bin whatever color fin you you'd like
and then the only thing I need to do now
is I need to align it with this other
one now there's a couple different ways
I can align it I could choose to select
it all and I could use the align again
if you want to do that go right ahead
or if you'd like to you can just
manually move it what I like to
sometimes do is I like to view it from
the top so I click on the word top here
on my view cube whenever I'm in the top
mode I like to switch to the
orthographic view and now I can take
this thing and I could just drag it to
where it is right in the center another
reason I chose to do that this time
instead of the align option is that I
happen to know that last time when I did
the alignment option I start to move it
later anyway I said those are
since my rocket now I think that they're
a little short so one thing that's nice
is I can still click on this object and
I can choose to make those spins taller
now the neat thing is is that stars
inside of the cylinder right but there's
nothing wrong with that it's just inside
and as far as CAD tools go they don't
care that it's overlapping so they're my
rocket is done you could you know change
the design however you see fit another
thing that you could choose to do is now
that it's kind of like a group you could
group so if you highlight the whole
thing there's two ways to do this you
can click and hold down shift and click
on each one individually that's fine but
I find that sometimes easier just like
drag a selection window around the whole
thing and you could choose to group it
if you would like now when you group it
it made it all the same color I
definitely don't want that so I click on
that color which is gray and I click on
multicolored and that lets it be a group
it's like it's a single group now but
it's different colors gold so there's
more things that you could do with your
rocket here but you now have a pretty
cool rocket one thing that's really easy
to do is you could duplicate it and then
now you have two rockets if you
duplicate it again now you have three
rockets and you know you could goof
around to your heart's content you can
choose to make Rockets bigger or smaller
one neat thing you can do with the
handles if you hold down shift when you
move it you could easily keep the
perspective the same so I just grab this
handle it does that but if I hold down
shift long move it it keeps it in the
correct perspective right well so I get
it to where you're happy with it I don't
really need all these extra rockets but
now I'm done my project and everybody
always asked this with Tinkercad how do
I save it and the answer is it saves it
for you right so it's just saved so you
can actually just go back to your kinker
dashboard and it keeps it saved alright
so let's start our last exercise for
today so the last exercise today is
we're
follow along with a link recent
Tinkercad blog post so this blog post
makes a house so what I'm going to do is
I'm going to kind of bring the tutorials
for this blog post up so that I can kind
of like jump back and forth between them
but if you want to you can just watch me
but you can see that he's gonna build
this house that's what we're gonna do
together and then once we're done with
that house we're gonna encourage you at
the end to make it your own right so
we're gonna go through his steps of
building the house and adding the roof
and then to make it your step is
something that you're going to do all by
yourself we're not gonna add piggies or
anything together right alright so go
ahead and go back to your dashboard and
click on create new design and so what
we're going to do is we're going to
build this house together and that's
gonna be our final exercise together
today so this house I guess technically
you could build it any size you wanted
but this tutorial recommends that you
make it a certain size 20 millimeters so
it's actually a very small house 40
millimeters and then 10 tall so let's go
ahead and start off by it by doing that
so I'm gonna go ahead and drag a block
over and what I want to do is I want to
make it 20 by 40 by 10 I'm there's all
kinds of ways to do that you could type
in those numbers over here if you wanted
or you could drag them with the handles
so I want one of the dimensions to be 40
I want one of the dimensions the height
to be 10 and I don't really care what
orientation you build it in right so you
can build it sideways like I did or or
the other way it doesn't matter
also notice that my grid is a little big
for this project as well I kind of like
for small projects to change my grid I'm
gonna do the same thing I did before I
clicked on edit grid and I made it 100
by 100 I had I updated it and so now
it's just kind of an appropriate sized
grid for one hour after being OCD I'm
going to move it to
but there's really no value in that and
I'm ready for the next step of the
tutorial so the next step of the
tutorial I won't bother to flip back and
forth to it it gets a little confusing
when I flip back and forth the next step
of the tutorial is to make a hole to cut
out the middle so that we can make all
four walls at the exact same time so
here's how the tutorial says to make a
hole one will do the same thing good way
to learn click on the block click on the
duplicate button so now this is sneaky
there's two blocks overlapping each
other
in the exact same space now how do you
how do you kind of know that I'll tell
you what I'm gonna do I'm gonna make one
of them a little taller than the other
and so I wanted to meet taller doesn't
matter how much taller and I'm gonna
take each of these sides and move it in
just one millimeter so you can see I
took that black handle I moved it by one
I'm gonna take this black handle and I'm
gonna move it in by exactly one and
you've got to get good at you know
rotating around and doing things I but I
want to take this back when I move it in
just one so now instead of 40 long it's
38 long because I took one off of each
side and then this is the the last side
over here I want to take this side yeah
one so you can see instead of being 20
wide it's 18 - I lost one so now I've
got two blocks now which is great but
this middle block I want to switch
instead of being a solid I want it to be
a hole so I click on hole and you guys
figured out what we're gonna do now how
to do and then I'm gonna take these two
parts my solid block in my hole and I'm
going to group I'm it's really neat when
you learn these skills and tutorials and
then you start like seeing them come to
life right so the easiest way to make
four walls is not to actually draw four
walls it's to draw one big box one hole
and then group them to subtract it out
pretty cool we're going to use that same
trick for the door so the dough
or and pause those you need if you're if
you're having trouble keeping up with me
no nobody at all the door is a
combination of a block which is huge and
a rounded roof so obviously they're
they're too big to start with but what
I'm gonna do is I'm going to assemble
them and then make them smaller so the
first thing I need to do to assemble
them as I need to put my blue roof up on
top of the house to do that I'm gonna
take my blue roof so I had this round
roof piece and I'm going to move it up
20 pixels so I'm dragging it up until
that gets to exactly 20 oh it's like
it's exactly 20 there and then I will go
ahead and click on this one and then
hold down shift and click on this one so
now I have only those two selected I
don't have my other things selected and
I do want to align them now so I'm going
to click on this align button up here
and I'm gonna line them in this
direction and that direction and the one
that should do is they should put the
roof right on the house which is great
now I'm going to shrink them down so
that the the right size for a doorway
but before I shrink them down I'm going
to group them so I've currently got them
both selected so I'm just gonna go and
click on the group button right now when
you click on group they become the same
colors whichever one you select it first
so in this case it will either be blue
or red depending on what you selected
first but it doesn't matter which color
was cuz we're gonna switch this thing to
be a hole right and the nice thing about
holes is they kind of show you the hole
so you can position it before you let it
go so we learned a lot of skills here
right we've learned about making two
objects we learned about aligning them
we've learned about moving them and now
what we're going to do is we're going to
position it so that it's a doorway well
the first thing I need to do to make
mine a doorway is I need to rotate it 90
degrees so that it becomes a doorway
that's just because of where I started
so I'm going to use my
rotate handles again I want to move at
exactly 90 degrees so I'm going to use
the inside the circle trick remember if
I was outside I could do like individual
degrees but I want to be inside the
circle so that I can easily move it
exactly 90 and then I want to make my
doorway quite a bit smaller so what I'm
gonna do is I'm gonna grab one of these
white handles and if I grab this white
handle on and move it you'll notice that
it just makes it like skinnier in one
direction but I want it to maintain its
proportions so I'm going to hold down
shift while I do it
and you'll notice that that
significantly changes how it behaves now
the whole thing grows proportionally I'd
shrinks I'm gonna actually shrink it
down where it's only four wide so it's a
teeny tiny door now in fact it's so
small that I lost my door
where are you doing and I'm going to put
my door to the front of my house cool
and being good at positioning I'm gonna
choose to get it perfectly centered so
you can see that now it's perfectly
centered in my house and now to actually
cut it out I select the the hole and I
select my part here and I group them
together that takes longer than I should
I'm gonna pause it I'm gonna go help my
camper and I imagine that you're gonna
need to help your camper a little bit as
well all right so I got my my camper
caught up there indeed there are a lot
of things here I think that I'm just
gonna let you work at your own pace but
just play until you get it working um
CAD modeling gets frustrating at times
but if you practice you'll get really
good at it and you get good at using the
mouse and you'll get rid of manipulating
things and this doorway is the hardest
thing we were doing today the last thing
we want to do is I want to add a roof so
I'm gonna grab a roof piece and drop it
on here I realized that my roof kind of
defaulted to the other direction as well
so I'm gonna rotate my roof this way
would have been easier if I just pick
the other direction but I didn't know
that at the time my roof what I wanted
to do is I want it to be 42 long so it's
just a little bit longer it's to longer
than the red that way it will kind of
overlap it and I want to make it 22 wide
because roofs always have a little bit
of an overhang right
so I took my rectangle I made it 22
by 40 the next thing I want to do is I
want to raise it up so I grabbed the
cone handle to raise it up 10
millimeters if only we're so easy in
real life to build things right you just
grab the roof and you just lift it up by
the cone right and then what I want to
do is I want to take this piece and this
piece and align them I so I can click on
the align button here I did that last
time and I certainly could do it again
but another way to do a lining that I
also like as I view it from the top I
put it in orthographic view and then I
just put it right right where I want
right so there it's right on the top and
then once I've got it where I want it I
switch back to the perspective view and
I can see that I now have a house pretty
cool if you would like just like we did
with the rocking you can optionally as
your last step select the whole thing
group that that'll make it the same
color but that's fine just click on the
color right here and say multicolor and
that's really optional because we're not
going to build any more of this and it
doesn't matter if it's one part or
multiple parts but I went ahead and made
it one part there I cool so there is my
house I consider that a finished product
I need to change the silly name they
they gave you here so I'm gonna call it
my house and that's actually where we're
gonna leave things for today if you
would like to try to make it your own
you can see that the person who created
this blog post went nuts he made all
kinds of things that's what I'd like for
you to do on your own so that's the end
of our day one I would encourage you to
try to build some things to make
get your own but that's the 3d modeling
tool in Tinkercad now this is actually
going to be our last day on 3d designs
right and so from here you've got enough
skills to play so just like as you think
of a project see if you can draw it but
you don't necessarily need more
tutorials from me I will say that you
might need to re-watch like some
tutorial things today or redo some of
those lessons so that you get really
good at those skills I've honestly I've
done those lessons like five times and
you can hit reset on them you can do
them again tomorrow we're gonna start
working with circuits so I look forward
to to see new them McKinley did you get
a finished house built today so she's
she's doing pretty good I was like she's
deaf got her house here and she's just
trying to get the finishing touches
alright you have plans for how you're
gonna make your house even better
alright
Gold great work today I'll help you
finish it up alright that's it look
forward to seeing it tomorrow
[Music]